

Pooja Rani

Curriculum Vitae

Objective

My main **research goal** is to conduct research, involving both industrial and academic collaborations, to support developers in various software engineering tasks such as program comprehension and maintenance tasks. My **research interests** are in the domain of Software Engineering (SE), human aspects of SE, empirical software engineering, mining repositories, data science, applied natural language processing (NLP) and machine learning (ML) to SE, and software documentation and evolution (with particular focus on IDE improvements).

Education

- 2018 now **Ph.D in Software Engineering**, supervised by Oscar Nierstrasz and Sebastiano Panichella, University of Bern, Switzerland.
- 2015 2017 **Masters of Engineering in Software System**, *Birla Institute of Technology and Science-Pilani*, Rajasthan, India, *CGPA 8.53*.
- 2011 2014 **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science**, *The Institution of Engineers*, India, *CGPA* 8.33.
- 2008 2011 **Diploma in Computer Science and Engineering**, Kalpana Chawla Goverment Polytechnic for Women, Ambala, Haryana, India, Percentage 83.

Work Experience

- July, 2017 Software Developer, at People Interactive Group pvt Itd. Mumbai, India.
 - Dec, 2017 Changing underlaying architecture and migrating code to node is framework
- Jan, 2017 Member of Technical Staff, at VMware Software India pvt Itd.Bangalore, India.
 - Jun, 2017 Developing a framework for automating identity access management flow
- Jul, 2011 **Software Tester**, at Samsung Research Institute, Noida, India.
- July, 2014 Creating test plan, resource planning, review meetings for mobile testing

Teaching Activities

- 2018 2021 Course Instructor, University of Bern, Bachelor & Master courses.
 - o Object-Oriented Programming: Bsc course, every Spring 2018, 2019, 2020, and 2021.
 - o Software Modeling Analysis: Msc course, Autumn 2018, and 2020.
- 2015 2016 **Teaching Assistant, BITS Pilani**, Bachelor courses.
 - o Computer Architecture: BE course, explaining verilog concepts, designing lab experiments.
 - o Computer Programming: BE course, C language concepts, organizing exercises.
 - o Software Testing: ME course, designing and correcting exercises

Supervision Activities

- 2019-2020 Msc thesis, University of Bern.
 - Supervised one master student and published the work in SANER, 2021
- 2018-2021 Bsc thesis, University of Bern & University of Zurich.

Supervised 5 bachelor students, currently writing two works

2018-2021 **Seminar projects, University of Bern**.

Supervised 3 seminar students on various topics

Publications

- JSS How to Identify Class Comment Types? A Multi-language Approach for Class Comment Classification, 2021.
- EMSE What do class comments tell us? An investigation of comment evolution and practices in Pharo Smalltalk, *To appear*, 2021.
- SCAM What do Developers Discuss about Code Comments?, To appear, 2021.
- SCAM One article under review, 2021.
 - JSS **A Systematic Literature Review on Comment Quality**, *Submission under preparation*, 2021.
- ICSE Speculative analysis for comment quality assessment, 2021.
- SANER Makar: A framework for multi-source studies based on unstructured data, 2021.
- SATToSE Software Analysis using Natural Language Queries, 2018.

Collaborations

- Sebastiano Panichella, Switzerland
- Mohammad Ghafari, New Zealand
- o Alexandre Bergel, Chille
- o Andrea Di Sorbo, Italy
- Nataliia Stulova, Switzerland
- Alessandra Gorla, Spain

Other Professional activities

- 2019-Today Board Member of CHOOSE group (Swiss group for Software Engineering
- 2018–2021 Co-reviewed papers of various international conferences and journals (SANER, TOSEM, ICSME)

Achievements and Awards

- 2018 Best presentation award at SATTOSE, 2018
- 2014 Qualified GATE 2015 Research fellowship from MHRD(Ministry of Human Research Development), India.
- 2012 Received the youngest Employee of the year award in Samsung.
- 2011 Batch Topper Secured 1st Rank in Diploma college.
- 2007 Silver Medal Won Silver Medal in state level Taekwondo Championship, Haryana.

More Details

Nationality - Indian

Language - English (C1), Hindi (native), German (A2.1)

Home page – https://poojaruhal.github.io/

Office page - http://scg.unibe.ch/staff/Pooja-Rani

Google Scholar - https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=2B8GcJ4AAAAJ

References

Available on Request